天使追魂
你好!
Hello!
是的  我是哈勒德·安卓
Yes, this is Harold Angel.
是的  在電話本中查大寫字母"A"
Yes, initial R, like in the phone book.
什麼?
Excuse me?
瓦恩薩普
Winesap.
赫爾曼·瓦恩薩普  瓦恩薩普與麥金托什?
Herman Winesap, Winesap & Mackintosh?
請等一下!
Hold on a second!
瓦恩薩普  瓦恩薩普與...
Winesap from Winesap&...
麥金托什公司的!我記好了!
Mackintosh. I've got it!
我當然知道代理人是幹什麼的
Of course I know what an attorney is.
就像律師  只不過價錢要貴很多
It's like a lawyer, only the bills are bigger.
好吧  我等你
Sure, I'll hold.
混蛋!
Asshole!
哈羅  瓦恩薩普先生?哈勒德·安卓
Hello, Mr. Winesap? Harold Angel.
是的  我可能有空
Yeah, I could be free.
是替你們公司幹嗎?
Would this be with your firm?
再講一次!
Gimme that again.
路易士...怎麼拼?
Louis...how do you spell that?
賽佛...好  這是什麼...外國姓?
Cyphre...okay. What is it...foreign?
你的客戶是一個外國人嗎?
Is your client a foreigner?
瓦恩薩普先生  你可不可以再和我說的詳細些?
Mr. Winesap, could you give me a few more details?
是的  我知道這個地方
Okay, I know the place.
那娷鰴o很遠  但我會准時到的
It's a long way up, but I can be there.
哈婺籊!馬上給我看看你們到底有多愛上帝!
Hallelujah! Show right now how much you love God!
我想要你們都表現出來!你們的機會來了!
I want you to show! It's your time!
打開你們的心扉  同時也打開你們的錢包!
Open up your hearts and open up your wallets!
打開你們的提包!
Open your purses!
打開你們的口袋!
Open your pockets!
全捐出來吧!贊美主!有人曾經講起過我
And give it up! Praise the Lord! Somebody has been talking about me
總坐著卡迪拉克到處走
riding around in a Cadillac.
如果你們愛我並願意全部奉獻給我
If you love me and want to give to me,
那我應該坐在勞斯萊斯車子中!
then I should be in a Rolls-Royce!
請跟我來  好嗎?
Would you come with me, please?
一個不幸的丈夫
An unfortunate husband
虔誠的一個信徒對自己的頭開了一槍  非常不幸
of one of Pastor John's flock took a gun to his head. Most unpleasant.
安卓先生?請進!
Mr. Angel? Please?
請允許我介紹我的客戶  路易士·賽佛先生
Allow me to introduce my client, Monsieur Louis Cyphre.
-你好  哈利·安卓  -很高興見到您  安卓先生
- Hi, Harry Angel. - Pleased to meet you, Mr. Angel.
頭次見面  我不想顯得太沒有禮貌
I don't want to appear impolite,
可是  你能給我看一下你的身份證嗎?
but do you have any l. D.?
哦  當然可以!在這...
Sure! Here...
怎麼樣?
How's that?
持槍證
Gun perm it
我並不是針對你...我這個人做事比較謹慎
Nothing personal. I'm a little over-cautious.
-你應該了解這些規矩的  -我了解...
- You know how these things are. - I know. So...
你是從哪兒知道我的?
How did you hear about me?
要我猜的話...你們肯定是在電話本中找到我的
I guess you guys just looked in the phone book.
以前總是這樣  因為...
Usually that's what happens. Because...
我姓"安卓"  在第一頁"A"那排
my name is "Angel", it's under "A"...
人們總是懶惰的  他們只看第一排
People are lazy. They see the first name
-而且...  -強尼·菲佛瑞.
- and...- Johnny Favorite.
什麼?
Excuse me?
你對強尼·菲佛瑞這個名字有沒有印象?
Do you by chance remember the name Johnny Favorite?
強尼·菲佛瑞  不  我沒印象
Johnny...No, I don't think so.
-你從沒聽說過他嗎?  -我應該知道他嗎?
- You never knew him? - Am I supposed to?
他在戰前是一個憂鬱歌手  在他們那行很出名
He was a crooner before the war, quite famous in his way.
-好吧  我告訴你  賽飛先生...  -是賽佛先生
- Well, I tell you, Mr. Cyphre... - Mr. Cyphre
對不起!
I'm sorry!
我一般情況下不參與那些
I usually don't get involved
牽涉到任何嚴重事情的工作
in anything very heavy.
我通常只是處理一些保險糾紛  離婚...
I usually handle insurance jobs, divorces,
這類簡單的事情
things of that nature.
有些時候運氣好的話...
If I'm lucky sometimes...
我也處理些人的事情  但是我不了解
I handle people. But I don't know
任何憂鬱歌手
no crooners
-或其他出名的人  -他的真正名字是利布林
- or anybody famous. - His real name was Liebling.
我也沒聽說過任何叫利布林的人
I don't know any Liebling, either.
你想讓我幹什麼?
What do you want from me?
-這個人欠你錢嗎?  -並不是你想得那回事
- Does this man owe you money? - Not quite.
我在強尼演唱事業剛剛起步的時候幫過他的忙
I helped Johnny at the beginning of his career.
你就像...他的經理人?
You were like...his agent?
不!
No!
不是這麼回事...
Nothing so...
賽佛先生有一份契約
Monsieur Cyphre has a contract.
如果他死了的話  有些東西我要收回來
Certain collateral was to be forfeited in the event of his death.
我們正在談論這個人已經死了嗎?
You're talking about a guy that's dead?
他在1943年被應征入伍
No, He was drafted 1943...
在北非"特殊娛樂服務"
in North Africa, "special entertainment service"
期間曾遭到一次突然襲擊  他的頭和臉受傷非常嚴重
There was attacked was badly injured about his head and face.
-他有...  -健忘症  你們叫它...
- He had...- Amnesia. I think you call it...
腦震蕩
Shell shock.
-對  -我知道是什麼感覺
- Exactly! - I know how that feels.
是嗎?你也服過兵役嗎?
Why? Were you in the services?
我只呆了很短一段時間
I was in for a short time.
但是我很討厭...
But I got a little fucked up.
對不起!他們送我回來  而我錯過了所有的事情:
Excuse me! They shipped me home, and I missed the whole shebang:
戰爭  獎章  所有的東西
the war, the medals, everything.
我猜你一定認為我很幸運
I guess you could say I was lucky.
強尼就沒那麼好命了  他回來後性格變得很怪
Johnny wasn't so lucky. He returned home a zombie.
他的朋友把他轉到北部的一家私人醫院
His friends had him transferred to a private hospital upstate.
在那媔i行一些強化的心理治療
There was some sort of radical psychiatric treatment involved.
他的律師被授權支付一些日常的開支
His lawyer is authorized to pay for some daily expenses
你也應該了解這種情況
But you know how it is.
他變成了植物人
He remained a vegetable,
而據我了解...我和他之間的合同就不受重視了!
and my contract was never honored.
這麼回事..
I see.
我不想顯得太唯利是圖
I don't want to sound mercenary.
我唯一感興趣的就是...他是否還活著?
My only interest in Johnny is in finding out if he's alive or dead.
每年我都會收到一份簽好的書面證明...
Each year my office receives a signed affidavit confirming
證明強尼·利布林確實還活著
that Johnny Liebling is indeed among the living.
但是上個周末  賽佛先生和我
But last weekend Monsieur Cyphre and l, just by chance,
恰好路過在波基普西的醫院(位於紐約)
were near the clinic in Poughkeepsie.
我們決定親自去查一下
We decided to check for ourselves,
但是我們只查到些令人誤解的信息
but we got misleading information.
他們在找借口!
The run-around!
我不希望有麻煩  也不喜歡大驚小怪
I didn't want to cause a scene, I hate any sort of fuss.
我想  也許你可以
I thought, perhaps you could
悄悄地開展一些調查...
subtly and in a quiet manner...
-你想讓我把它查清楚?  -對
- You want me to check it out. - Check it out!
很奇怪  我好像以前見過你
I have a feeling I've met you before.
不知道  我沒什麼印象
I don't know, I don't think so.
你聽說過強尼·菲佛瑞嗎?
Do you remember the name Johnny Favorite?
他的真正名字是利布林
His real name was Liebling.
我唯一感興趣的就是...他是否還活著?
My only interest in Johnny is in finding out if he's alive or dead.
-我可以幫到你嗎?  -我叫哈利·康羅伊
- May I help you? - My name is Harry Conroy
國家健康協會的
from the National lnstitute of Health.
你想見什麼人嗎?
Is there anyone in particular you want to see?
協會正在開展一項關於不可治愈外傷案件的調查
The lnstitute is conducting a survey of incurable trauma cases.
我聽說你們這兒有個病人符合我們的條件
I understand you have a patient here fitting that description?
沒有預約的話  我是不會讓你見任何人的
We can't let you see anyone without an appointment.
我很感激  但是也許你可以檢查一下文件
I appreciate that, but maybe you could check the files
看看我有沒有找錯地方
and make sure I'm on the right track.
沒必要的話  我不想打擾任何人
I don't want to bother anybody unnecessarily.
好嗎?謝謝你
Okay? Thank you.
病人的名字是什麼?
What's the name of the patient?
利布林  喬納森·利布林
Liebling, Jonathan Liebling.
等一下  我查查看
One moment please, I'll check.
上個周末也是你上班嗎?
Were you working here last weekend?
-不是  我那天輪休  -都幹了些什麼開心的事呀?
- No, day off. - Did you do anything nice?
我姊妹的婚禮
My sister's wedding.
我們確實有利布林先生  但是他被轉走了
We did have a Mr. Liebling, but he was transferred.
-你確定嗎?  -這上面是這麼記錄的
- You sure? - That's what it says.
-是什麼時候的事?  -幾年前  43年12月.
- And when was that? - Years ago, in December '43.
我可以看一看嗎?謝謝
May I take a look at this? Thanks.
這是最近寫的嗎?
Is this recent?
-這是個老文件  -但這是圓珠筆的字跡!
- It's an old file. - It's in ballpoint!
43年不大可能有圓珠筆
They weren't big on ballpoint in '43.
這是圓珠筆跡嗎?
Is that ballpoint?
我看著也是!他們那時沒有圓珠筆嗎?
Well, I'll be! They didn't have ballpoints back then?
沒有
No.
這堻o個...
This here
福勒博士
Dr. Fowler,
他仍然在這堣u作嗎?
does he still work here?
僅是兼職的  他年紀很大了
Just part-time, he's old.
謝謝你
Thank you.
你晚上都是這會回來嗎?
Time for your evening fix?
你是誰?你怎麼進來的?
Who are you? How did you get in here?
郵箱寄進來的  我是一個私家偵探
Through the mailslot. I'm a private detective.
破門而入是嚴重罪行
Breaking and entering is a crime,
不管你是什麼人都一樣
whoever or whatever you are.
嗨老兄  那你叫警察呀!
Hey man, call the police!
你那樣做的話  警察可能會發現你在冰箱
Which you won't do in case they discover your opium den
私藏冰毒!
in the icebox!
我是一位醫生  我完全有權在家保存一些醫藥制品
I'm a doctor. I'm perfectly entitled to keep pharmaceuticals at home.
去和別人說這些!你這堣ㄥ僅是一兩瓶那麼簡單
Tell it to somebody else! We're not talking about a Band-Aid
-你上癮多久了?  -你到底想幹什麼?
- or a tube of unguent. How long you been hooked? - What do you want?
一些有關強尼·利布林的資料
Information about Johnny Liebling.
很多年以前  我治療過一個叫這個名字的病人
I treated a patient of that name many years ago.
我不是那麼好糊弄的
I'm not fooling around.
要麼你給我一些有用的資料...
Either you give me some answers
要麼我親自打電話給警察
or I'll call the police myself.
我剛才看到樓上在做著一些東西
I've seen the works cooking upstairs,
那玩意兒肯定不是索爾克先生(美國細菌學家)的疫苗
and it ain't Mr. Salk's vaccine.
他是戰爭期間的一個演藝人員  是個精神病的案例
He was an entertainer during the war, a neuro case.
沒有機會恢複
No chance of recovery,
因此我把他轉到奧爾巴尼(位於紐約)的V.A.醫院
so I transferred him to a V.A. hospital in Albany.
我不想讓你吃驚  但是我檢查過  他不在那
I hate to shake you up, but I checked, and he's not there.
你辦了假的轉院手續
You faked the transfer.
因為他最近有一個訪客  12年來的第一次
Because he recently had a visitor, the first in 1 2 years.
名人  嗯?
Popular guy, eh?
現在他在哪?
Where is he now?
-我不知道...  -過來!
- I don't know...- Come here!
自從他來這埵禨|  我就沒見過他
I haven't seen him since he was a patient here.
你在冒冷汗!看看你!
You're in a cold sweat! Look at you!
你甚至等不及我走  就想給自己來一針
You can't wait for me to leave so you can raid the icebox.
你越早把事情講清楚  就越早能舒服一下
The sooner you get out with it, the sooner you can shoot up.
我再問你一次:他在哪?
I'll ask you again: Where is he?
我不知道
I don't know.
幾年前的一個晚上  突然來了一幫人
Some people came one night years ago.
他和他們一起坐車走了
He got in the car with them and left.
他坐車走了?我以為這家夥是個植物人呢
He got into a car? I thought this guy was a vegetable.
開始他是處於昏迷中  但很快就恢複過來了
At first he was in a coma but he quickly recovered.
但是他仍然有健忘症
But he still suffered from amnesia.
朋友
The friends.
這些朋友是誰?
Who were the friends?
他的名字是  開利  愛德華·開利
His name was Kelley, Edward Kelley.
我不認識那個小姐  她始終呆在汽車
The young lady I don't know. She stayed in the car.
他們帶他到哪去了?
Where did they take him?
南方  那個男的說:"我們送他回家"
Down South. The man said: "We're taking him home."
-給了你什麼好處?  -2萬5千塊
- And what was the deal? - $25,000.
為什麼給你這麼多?
For what?
我偽造證據使他看起來仍在醫院
I was supposed to pretend that he was still a patient in hospital.
醫院管理部門沒有懷疑嗎?
Didn't the administration suspect?
他們為什麼會懷疑?我不斷的更新醫療紀錄
Why should they? I kept the charts
而且賬單按時支付的話  別人是不會懷疑的
up to date. And no one asks questions when the bills get paid.
告訴我一些關於強尼·利布林的情況
Tell me about Johnny Liebling.
-他長得什麼樣子?  -不知道他的臉被毀容了
- What did he look like? - No idea. His face was damaged.
他做了面部整容手術  他走的那天臉上還紮著繃帶
He had facial reconstruction. He was in bandages the day he left.
關於開利  你能和我講些什麼嗎?
What can you tell me about Kelley?
時間太長了  我只有些模糊的記憶
It's too long ago. I only have a vague memory.
他穿著得體  有南方的口音
He was well dressed and had a southern accent.
我實在是想不起來了
I truly don't remember.
好吧  醫生躺下休息會兒吧!
All right, Doc. Have a lie down.
我出去吃個牛肉漢堡
I'm going out to grab a cheeseburger.
也許你冷靜幾個小時會想起些新的東西來
Maybe a few hours cold turkey will refresh your memory.
小心點兒!
Watch yourself!
躺下睡一會兒
We're going to take a little nap, sit your ass down.
好好想一想
We're going to clear your mind.
我現在出去等我回來的時候
I'm going out. When I get back,
我會從冰箱媯鳩A帶點好東西  好嗎?
I'll fix you some goodies from the icebox, alright?
把我想知道的告訴我  我就再也不會找你麻煩了
Tell me what I want to know and you'll get rid of me forever.
我回來了  醫生!我給你帶了些好東西!
I'm back, Doc! I brought you a little something!
我想你可能不會要漢堡包
I didn't think you'd want a cheeseburger...
我會的了!再見!
I will! Bye!
嗨  埃莉!
Hi, Ellie!
那個是你的男朋友嗎?
Is that your boyfriend?
他有輛車?
He's got a car and everything?
等會兒見!
See you later!
-你見到他了嗎?  -沒有
- Did you see him? - No.
為什麼沒有?
Why not?
-這事有點困難  -為什麼?
- It would've been difficult. - Why?
為什麼?因為他不在那
Why? Because he's not there.
強尼·菲佛瑞在12年前穿著他最好的衣服
Johnny Favorite walked out of the clinic 1 2 years ago,
離開了那家醫院而且他的臉經過整容
in his best suit, with a new face wrapped in bandages...
走的時候還包著繃帶
and a headache.
他和一個叫開利的家夥一起離開的
He left with a guy called Kelley
還有一個女的  你認識這個開利嗎?
and a girl. Do you know this Kelley?
這個叫開利的付錢雇用一個
It seems this Kelley paid off some bent
叫福勒的醫生處理遺留問題
doctor called Fowler
這些年都是這個醫生在做手腳掩飾
to pinch hit for your guy. He's covered up for him all these years.
看來我們的強尼已很神秘地失蹤了
Looks like our Johnny has
-看起來是這麼回事  -就是如此
- a perfect disappearing act. - It seems so.
你知道他們是怎麼形容蝸牛的嗎?
But you know what they say about slugs.
不知道  他們怎麼說?
No, what do they say about slugs?
蝸牛總是在它走的路上留下痕跡  粘液
They always leave slime in their tracks.
-你能找到他  -不  我不會去找他
- You'll find him. - No, I won't find him.
因為我遺漏一個小細節
Because I left out one little detail.
這個福勒博士死了
This Dr. Fowler ended up dead
腦漿四濺
with his fucking brains blown out.
-是你殺了他嗎?  -不是!
- Did you kill him? - No!
但是警察可能認為是我做的
But the cops might think I did.
我收你125塊一天  僅僅是幫你找個失蹤的人
I took on a $1 25-a-day missing persons job for you.
現在  我反倒成了一個謀殺嫌疑犯
Now, I'm a murder suspect.
到此為止!我不幹了
That's it! I'm out.
這些是在你的職業生涯中必然會遇到的危險
Such are the hazards of your profession.
如果你覺得是價錢在困擾你的話  我還可以再加
If the fee bothers you, we'll adjust it.
是你在煩擾我!
You bother me!
我對死亡感覺最接近的時候...
The closest I ever come to death...
也就僅僅是看著靈車從第二大街經過
is watching a hearse go by on 2nd Avenue.
我只能承受到這個程度
That's the way I like it.
你是害怕嗎?
Are you afraid?
是的  我很害怕
Yeah, I'm afraid.
我會通知我的律師馬上寄給你5千的支票.
I'll instruct my lawyer immediately to send you a check for $5,000.
如果你不想幹  我會找其他人
If you don't want the job, I'll engage someone else.
五千美元?
5,000?
你很想找到這個強尼  是嗎?
You want this Johnny pretty bad, eh?
我不喜歡我的帳目混亂
I don't like messy accounts.
一些宗教認為蛋是靈魂的象征  你知道嗎?
Some religions think the egg is the symbol of the soul, did you know that?
不知道
No.
你想要一個蛋嗎?
Would you like an egg?
不  謝謝你  我對雞過敏
No, thank you. I got a thing about chickens.
-過了十一點了  你遲到啦  -對不起
- It's after eleven, you're late. - I'm sorry.
-你拿到了嗎?  -如果我失去工作的話
- You get it? - If I lose my job,
我會當你的秘書
I'll come and be your secretary.
我不可能付給你"泰晤士報"的薪資
I couldn't pay you what the "Times" pays.
此外  他們也不會讓你走
Besides, they won't miss it.
嗨  強尼  你到底是個什麼角色?
Hi, Johnny, where the fuck are you?
他真的是一個憂鬱歌手
He really was a crooner,
像你說的  我沒想到他這麼有名
like you said. I didn't realize he was so big.
他曾在一個叫斯巴德·新普森的樂團工作  他們都死了
He was in a band called the Spider Simpson Orchestra. They're all dead.
只有斯巴德還在這個城市
Only Spider is here in town.
-在哪?  -我全都寫在上面了
- Where? - I wrote it all down.
檔案中的同性戀女子有些可疑
The dyke in the archive is suspicious.
我的老板有好多年都不看這些檔案了
My boss hasn't researched the story in years.
你可以把檔案拿走
You can get the files.
斯巴德現在在138大街的一個老人院中
Spider is in an old people's home on 1 38th Street.
唉  我又得去一次黑人區
Oh, I get to go to Harlem again.
這有一張強尼和土斯·史威特的合影  一個吉他手
There was a picture of Johnny with Toots Sweet, a guitar player.
已經很多年沒人聽說過他了!
No one's heard of him for years!
強尼和一個很有錢的女人訂婚
Johnny was engaged to a rich broad,
瑪格麗特·克洛斯馬克  她爸爸擁有一半的路易斯安那
Margaret Krusemark. Her dad owns half of Louisiana.
他倆兒在一個中學舞會認識強尼和她扯上了
Met him at a high school prom. Johnny shit on her,
她就回去找她爸爸
and she went back to Daddy.
有很多和他們的符咒有關的事情
There's lots on their spells.
符咒  你說符咒是什麼意思?
Spells, what do you mean, spells?
就像蠑螈的眼睛
The eye of a newt,
青蛙的腳趾...諸如此類的東西?
toe of a frog and that kind of shit?
她看起來有一點點怪
Seems she was a bit of a crackpot.
沒事會做些藥水...下下咒什麼的
Casting spells at society do's and stuff.
沒參加什麼組織嗎?
Didn't go down too well with the lvy League stiffos.
她在威爾斯萊利(位於紐約長島)是很出名的巫婆
She was known as the Witch of Wellesly.
我做的漂亮嗎?
Did I do good?
太棒了!看看我們有些什麼
Great! So what've I got
一個帶有宗教色彩像瘋子一樣的客戶
A religious loonie as a client.
我必須找到這個"金嗓子"強尼
I gotta find Johnny "Golden Tonsils"
而我們現在沒有一點頭緒
and we don't know where he is.
而他呢  可能連自己是誰都不知道
And he probably doesn't know who he is.
還有一個住在黑人區的--當過樂隊指揮的老家夥
I got a geriatric bandleader in a home in Harlem.
一個叫土斯·史威特的吉他手
I got a guitar player called Toots Sweet.
我們還有什麼?
What else have I got?
迫切的希望?
A hard-on?
你沒事吧?
Are you okay?
一月三日
January 3rd,
1955年  客戶:路易士·賽佛
1 955. Client: Louis Cyphre.
附錄:瓦恩薩普與麥金托什  代理人
Copy: Winesap & Mackintosh,
記錄如下  強尼·菲佛瑞在12年前就已離開...
attorneys. As reported, Johnny Favorite has not been
在波基普西的莎拉·多德醫院
in the Sarah Dodd Clinic in Poughkeepsie for the last 1 2 years.
他被一個叫愛德華·開利的男人和一個女人帶走
He was taken away by a man called Edward Kelley and a girl.
女的身份無法確認
The girl is unidentified.
開利付了2萬5給福勒醫生
Kelley paid a Dr. Fowler $25,000 to falsify reports
偽造強尼的住院紀錄..
stating that Favorite was still in the hospital.
醫生現在死了
The doctor is now deceased.
種種跡象顯示強尼在出意外前
Before Johnny's accident it seemed
事業正處於高峰期
like his career was going great,
一直到他開始遺棄他的支持者
until he started to dump on everyone.
我跟蹤記錄了斯巴德.新普森
I tracked down Spider Simpson,
強尼以前的樂隊指揮
Johnny's old bandleader. He resides
他住在138大街的林肯長老會教收容站
at the Lincoln Presbyterian Hospice
強尼還有一個好朋友  一個叫土斯·史威特的吉他手
on 1 38th Street. Johnny also had a good buddy, a guitar player
土斯回阿爾及爾那堨h了
called Toots Sweet. Toots went back to Algiers.
是在新奧爾良的那個阿爾及爾
That's Algiers in New Orleans.
我估計瑪格麗特可能在那兒  有可能強尼也在那
I think maybe Margaret went back there, and maybe Johnny, too.
哦  對了!根據斯巴德描述  強尼還有個秘密情人
Oh, yeah! According to Spider, Johnny had a secret love.
一位黑人女士  叫伊文捷琳·普勞德富特
A black lady called Evangeline Proudfoot.
伊文捷琳  在黑人區經營一家靈異物品商店
Evangeline ran some kind of spooky store in Harlem
店名叫"曼寧卡特"
called "Mammy Carter's."
你不需要知道這些  賽佛我想..
You don't need to know that, Cyphre. I think
秘密的情人就讓她維持秘密吧
a secret love should stay secret.
有一個人
The only person
強尼每隔一段時間就會去找他
who Johnny was seeing regularly
一個住在長島上(位於紐約)的叫卓拉夫人的看手相的人
was a palm reader in Coney lsland called Madame Zora.
你是  易茲嗎?
Are you lzzy?
-是的  -正在欣賞夕陽  嗯?
- Yes. - Looks like the last bit of sun, eh?
走廊堛漕滬茪H說也許你能幫到我
The guy in the arcade over there told me you might be able to help me.
我正在找  卓拉夫人
I'm looking for Madame Zora.
我知道她  戰前我老婆的朋友
I know her, friend of the wife before the war.
-她是一個有錢的手相家  是嗎?  -是啊!
- She was a fortune teller, right? - And then some!
我討厭那些靠騙人吃飯的狗東西!她和我老婆關系很好
I hate those hocus-pocus bitches! Her and the wife got along real well.
我老婆是個浸信會教友  哦  這!
Wife's a baptist. Oh, here!
給鼻子帶個套兒!
Have a nose shield!
沒事的  拿一個  我在走道塈鋮鴗F一大盒
Go on, take one. I found a whole boxful under the boardwalk.
現在陽光不是很猛
There's not much sun right now.
是的  但是也不會下雨
Yeah, but it keeps the rain off too.
你聽說過一個叫強尼·菲佛瑞的人嗎?
Ever hear of a Johnny Favorite?
-唱歌的?  -是的  他過去經常拜訪卓拉夫人
- The singer? - Yeah, he used to visit Madame Zora.
聽說過他  但是什麼也不知道  你去問問我老婆
Heard of him, but don't know nothing. Ask the wife.
她總是跟著收音機唱些難聽的歌
She always sings stupid tunes off the radio.
她對這些東西很了解
She knows all that shit.
-她喜歡水  嗯?  -不  她討厭它
- She likes the water, eh? - She hates it.
她正在做運動  她認為這些對她的靜脈曲張有好處
She's getting on the heavy side. She thinks it's good for varicose veins.
好的  謝謝
Alright, thanks.
夏天的時候你在這媟F什麼?
What do you do here in the summer?
在這兒打老鼠
Bite the heads off the rats.
-冬天呢?  -一樣
- And in the winter? - The same.
對不起!
Excuse me!
我剛和你的丈夫聊過
I was just talking to your husband.
我正在打聽關於卓拉夫人的事
I was inquiring about Madame Zora.
是的  我在戰前就認識她
Yeah, I knew her before the war,
卓拉夫人  你說的是她嗎?
Madame Zora, you say?
是的  她是一個有錢的吉普賽手相家!
Yeah, she was a gypsy fortune teller!
在我家隔壁開了個店  她肯定不是吉普賽人
Had the booth across the boardwalk from me. She was a debutante not a gypsy,
而且她不僅僅只會看手相
and she did more than just read tea leaves.
你見過她和一個叫強尼·菲佛瑞的人在一起過嗎?
Did you ever see her with a guy called Johnny Favorite?
見過  他很可愛
Yeah, he was cute.
她被他迷住了  人們都叫他"金嗓子"
She was stuck on him. He was called "Golden Tonsils".
我聽過他所有的歌
I knew all his tunes.
那你聽說過一個叫瑪格麗特·克洛斯馬克的人嗎?
Have you ever heard of a Margaret Krusemark?
別冒傻氣了  哥們!
Don't be a gazoony, fellah!
卓拉夫人就是瑪格麗特·克洛斯馬克
Madame Zora was Margaret Krusemark.
好的  她怎麼樣了?
Well what happened to her?
收拾東西回她南方的老家去了
Packed up her stuff and went back home, down south.
你知不知道  我到哪堨i以找到強尼·菲佛瑞?
You have any idea where I could find Johnny Favorite?
不知道  也許在墓地
No, maybe the cemetery.
想要聽到他的其中一首歌曲嗎?
Want to hear one of his tunes?
謝謝你的鼻子套  我去的地方正好要用到它
Thanks for the nose shield. I'm going to need it where I'm going.
布魯克林?
In Brooklyn?
-不  是路易斯安那(美國南部一州)  -好極了
- Louisiana. - Nice.
他去哪?
Where'd he go?
僅限有色人種
For colored patrons only
安卓先生?抱歉讓你等  但是你有點兒早了
Mr. Angel? Sorry to keep you waiting, but you're a little early.
我的電話不是很清楚
I had a bad line.
沒聽清你說的是4:00還是4:30.
I didn't know if you said 4:00 or 4:30.
-真是個好地方!  -是的  我在這塈b得很開心
- This is a wild place you got here! - Yes, I've been very happy here.
我以前從沒看過相  要花很長時間嗎?
I've never had my fortune read before. Does it take long?
我現在就開始  通常要花幾天做一個圖表
I'll take the details now. It usually takes a couple of days to do a chart.
茶?
Tea?
你想要一些茶嗎?
Do you want some tea?
是的  謝謝你
Yes, thank you.
大吉嶺茶(印度)  茉莉花還是烏龍茶?
Darjeeling, jasmine or oolong?
-烏龍茶  -很少人喜歡烏龍茶
- Not many people like oolong.
你會彈鋼琴嗎?
Do you play the piano?
不  不是很懂
No, not exactly.
唱歌呢?
Sing?
我能唱兩句  但是不...不好聽
I can carry a tune, but no...not really.
這個難看的家夥是誰?
Who is this mean looking guy?
我的父親
My father.
對不起!
I'm sorry!
沒事  他也不喜歡這張照片
Don't worry, he hates it too.
他看起來像過去那些海盜電影堛漱H  他叫什麼名字?
He looks like one of those guys in an old pirate movie. What's his name?
-伊桑  -伊桑·克洛斯馬克...
- Ethan. - Ethan Krusemark...
好吧  我告訴你  我從不看伊桑的電影
Well, I tell you, I never saw any of Ethan's movies.
你會說法語嗎?
Do you speak French?
我來自布魯克林
I'm from Brooklyn.
-最好別吸煙  -好
- I would prefer it if you didn't smoke. - That's okay.
乳酪或糖?
Cream or sugar?
就這樣挺好  謝謝你
Straight up is fine, thank you.
我需要你准確的出生日期
I need your exact date of birth.
當然!
Sure!
我在2月14日出生...
I was born on February 14th...
...1918年  剛好是情人節
...1918, on Valentine's day.
很有意思!我以前認識個人也在這天出生
How curious! I used to know a boy who was born on that exact same day.
是嗎  你知道了  所有士兵的家都在
Well, you know how it is, all the soldiers home on leave and all.
也許我們可以把你這個朋友的圖表拿出來用
Maybe we could pull your friend's chart...
省的浪費時間
and save ourselves some time.
我不這麼認為  每個人都是不一樣的
I don't think so. Every person is very different. I don't think
我想你也不會喜歡他的圖表
you'd like his chart.
出生的地方?
Place of birth?
布魯克林  紐約  你的朋友是一個性情古怪的人嗎?
Brooklyn, New York. Was your friend a jerk or something?
你可以這麼說
You could say that.
我猜你們可能相處得不好
I guess you didn't get along.
你和強尼
You and Johnny.
你和強尼·菲佛瑞?
You and Johnny Favorite?
-你是誰?  -我是他在部隊堛漲挩啎
- Who are you? - I was an old army buddy.
我想你們兩個是那種...
I thought you two were kinda...
好吧  我不是他的戰友
Look, I ain't no army buddy,
我只是個受雇找尋資料的人
I'm just a guy who was paid to snoop around.
說實話  我不是情人節那天生的
To tell the truth, I wasn't born on Valentine's day.
我只對強尼的未來感興趣
It's Johnny's future I'm interested in.
強尼沒有未來  他死了
Johnny has no future, he's dead.
他12年前就死了  我想你該走了
He died 1 2 years ago. I'd like you to leave.
我知道你肯定在想...
I know you're thinking...
這個偷偷摸摸到處刺探消息的人是誰?
who is this creep poking his snitch in everything.
我不想讓你感覺我太多管閑事  但是...
I don't want to sound nosy, but...
他死了  安卓先生
He's dead, Mr. Angel.
即使她沒死  在我心堨L也是死的
And if he isn't, he is to me.
他肯定把你傷害得很深!
He must've hurt you pretty bad!
我們每個人都有自己的傷心事
We all have our scars.
我對這個家夥不是很了解
I don't know too much about the guy,
但是  他離開你實在是太蠢了
but he must've been stupid to let you go.
謊言和殘忍對某些人來說是很容易的
Lies and cruelty come very easily to some people.
很遺憾  我真的希望你能幫我看看手相
Pity, I really would've liked to have gotten my palm read.
那樣我就可以把你的手多握一會兒
Then I could have held your hand just a little longer.
我不認為你會喜歡我看見的事情
I don't think you'd like what I see.
非常漂亮的項鏈!
Very pretty necklace!
你有沒有很爽啊  強尼!
You got any High John
-一種草藥根?  -藥粉還是整條的?
- the Conquerer root? - Powdered or hanging?
我也不知道
I'm not really sure.
被雨淋的咳嗽了  嗯?
Caught in the rain, eh?
二個草藥根  1塊2
Two roots, $1 .20.
順便問一下  我在黑人區有個熟人
I have a question. I had an acquaintance in Harlem
她過去也是賣這些的
who used to deal in the root.
名字是  伊文捷琳聽說過她嗎?
Name was Evangeline. Heard of her?
自從那首詩出來後  基本上這堥C個人都叫伊文捷琳
Practically everyone around here is called Evangeline. After the poem.
你聽說過那首詩嗎?
Do you know it?
是的  我知道它
Yeah, I know it.
這個熟人在黑人住宅區中有一間商店
This acquaintance had a store in Harlem...
店名和你的一樣
and it was the same name:
-"卡特"  -每個人都用這個名字  先生
- "Carter." - Everybody uses the name, mister.
就像"華德·強森"  但是這堣~是正宗
Like "Howard Johnson," but this is the real place.
她的名字是普勞德富特
Her name was Proudfoot.
伊文捷琳·普勞德富特?
Evangeline Proudfoot?
我認識她  她住在紐約的時候經常回來
I knew her. She used to come back all the time when she lived in New York.
-你知道她現在哪媔?  -她生病死了
- Do you know where she is now? - She got sick and died.
她回到了神的庇護所
She went back to the Holy Shelter swamp...
被埋在阿曼德維爾(位於阿爾及利亞))
and was buried in Armandville.
她正在等候某些人
She was waiting on some fellah.
-就像詩中寫的那樣?  -是的
- Just like in the poem? - Yep.
一塊二
$1 .20.
-她等的是誰?  -她從沒說過
- Who was the guy? - She never told.
好  謝謝
Okay, thanks.
-租一個星期  是嗎?  -是  最多一星期
- A week, you say? - At the most.
這是什麼?
What is it?
有什麼好哭的呢?
Why are you crying?
我們去看奶奶  誰在那兒呀?
We're going to Grandma. What's there?
奶奶
Grandma.
走吧
Let's go.
把手給我
Give me your hand.
對不起!這是一個住在長島的家夥給我的
I'm sorry! I got these off a guy in Coney lsland.
一個瘋家夥
Some crazy guy.
對不起
I'm sorry.
別哭了
Stop crying.
我想和你媽媽聊一會兒
I was hoping I could talk with your mother.
你來得有點晚了  你認識她嗎?
You're a little late. Did you know her?
不  我從沒見過她  但我有些問題想問問她
No, I never met her but I was hoping she could answer some questions for me.
你是警察嗎?
Are you a cop?
不是  我的名字是哈利·安卓
No, my name is Harry Angel.
我是一個私家偵探
I'm a private detective.
-你叫什麼...?  -艾普芙尼
- So what's...? - Epiphany.
你媽媽給你起了個很好聽的名字
Your mama left you with a very beautiful name.
除了名字什麼也沒給我留下
And not much else.
實際上  我正在找你母親的一個朋友
Actually, I'm looking for a friend of your mother's,
一個叫強尼·菲佛瑞的人
a guy called Johnny Favorite.
我見過她所有的朋友  但從沒聽說過這個人
I met all her friends but never anyone called Favorite.
倒黴!
Shit!
我對雞有些敏感
I got a thing about chickens.
這個人戰前在紐約和你媽是好朋友
This Favorite was friends with your mother in New York city before the war.
好吧  她沒和我說過
Well, she never told me.
媽媽有許多男朋友  她喜歡男人
Mama had a lot of guys. She liked men.
那...另外一個叫土斯·史威特的呢?
How about a guy called Toots Sweet?
他是菲佛瑞的一個朋友認識他嗎?
He was a friend of Favorite. Know him?
-不認識  -他是一個吉他手
- No. - He was a good guitar player.
我今晚正要去看他表演
I was going to catch his act tonight.
我會呆在鎮子的一個旅館
I'm going to be staying in town, in a hotel.
如果你記起些對我有用的事
If you remember anything
打電話給我
that might help me, give me a call.
你是一個非常漂亮的少女
You're a very pretty girl,
艾普芙尼  你的名字適合你
Epiphany, your name suits you.
這些發瘋的雞!
These crazy chickens!
你找這個強尼·菲佛瑞幹什麼?
What are you after him for, Johnny Favorite?
不是我找他  我只是受雇查出他在哪
I'm not after him. I'm just being paid to find out where he is.
他可能在地底下
He could be 6 feet under.
那我只好買一把鏟子了
Then I'll have to buy a shovel.
你好嗎  親愛的?
How are you, sugar?
你怎能唱出那麼動人的音韻  史威特先生
Some beautiful tune
我叫土斯  小子!謝謝
you were singing there, Mr. Sweet.
可以請你喝一杯嗎?
Toots, son! Thanks. - Buy you a drink?
不用了  今天老板請客特制雞尾酒
Mine's on the house. Special cocktail.
別管堶惟韙F什麼  先喝一大杯再說
Whatever's in it gives a big kick.
你知道嗎  幾年前我在紐約看過你表演
You know, I heard you play years ago in New York.
戰前在老  迪基·威爾斯酒吧
Before the war at the old Dickie Wells Bar.
你和一個  叫強尼·菲佛瑞的家夥合作表演得不錯
You were having it up pretty good with a guy called Johnny Favorite.
-是的  我都快忘了  -你和他是好朋友  是嗎?
- Yeah, I vaguely remember. - You and he were buddies, weren't you?
不是  他錄了我的其中一支歌  你是星探還是作家?
No, he recorded one of my songs. Say, are you a dick or a book writer?
都不是  我是一個新聞記者
Neither. I'm a journalist
我正在寫一些關於...
and I'm doing this piece
強尼和斯巴德·新普森  管弦樂隊的文章
about Johnny and the Spider Simpson Orchestra.
斯巴德打起鼓來就像兩只長耳朵大野兔在性交!
Spider played them drums like two jackrabbits fucking!
我沒有太多的時間要先去小個便  然後還要回去工作
Haven't got much time. Got to piss, spit and get back to work.
試一下這些雞尾酒  喝完後你就隨便編個故事
Try one of those cocktails. Then you can make the whole thing up as you like.
反正你們平常都是這麼幹的
That's what you usually do, anyway.
我連小個便都不行嗎!
I can't even take a piss!
我只是想談談關於...
I just wanted to talk about...
強尼·菲佛瑞和伊文捷琳·普勞德富特的事
Johnny Favorite and Evangeline Proudfoot.
我什麼都沒隱瞞  卻是一無所知
I'm too big to go hiding under beds. I don't know nothing.
我只對雞尾酒感興趣  他媽的!
I'm only interested in cocktails. Fuck!
怎麼回事?
What's going on?
沒事!管好你自己  我只想撒尿!
Nothing! Mind your own business. I want to piss!
滾出去
Get outta here,
否則的話你會後悔被生出來
or you'll wish your little white ass was never born.
拜托!我對雞有些敏感
Please! I've got a thing about chickens.
不要再和我胡說八道了!
End of bullshit time!
我看得清清楚楚...
I've had a good look at you and young Epiphany
你和艾普芙尼一起用雞搞那些祭祀
doing your hot shoe number with the chicken.
聽清楚!
Listen!
我才不信這些伏都教的鬼法術  我來自布魯克林
I ain't up on this voodoo shit. I'm from Brooklyn.
我們都不是虔誠的教徒
We ain't all Baptists here.
這個姓普勞德富特的姑娘到底是幹什麼的?
What's with this Proudfoot girl?
她是一個曼波女祭司
She's a mambo priestess,
和她的媽媽一樣  從她13歲開始就是
like her mom. Has been since she was 1 3.
你上一次看見強尼·菲佛瑞和雞跳這些怪舞是什麼時候?
When was the last time you saw Johnny Favorite at a chicken dance?
-他那時經常圍著她媽媽轉  -我在戰前就沒見過他
- He used to run around with Ma mambo. - I ain't seen him since before the war.
那廁所堛甄腳是什麼意思?
And the chicken foot in the john?
那是警告我嘴太快了
It means I got a big mouth.
還不夠快  你嘴堛滌閂P星是什麼東西?
It's not big enough. What's this fucking star
我告訴你
in your mouth? I'll tell you what.
我把旅店的電話號碼告訴你
I'll give you my hotel number.
你打聽到什麼事就給我打個電話
Gimme a call if you hear anything.
你要知道
You never know.
下次你再收到一個雞腳的話  你可能需要幫忙
Next time you get a delivery of a chicken foot, you might need help.
我最關心的是  死雞才是個好雞
As far as I'm concerned, any dead chicken is a good chicken.
只有警察和壞消息從不敲門
Only cops and bad news don't knock.
只有私人偵探總睡懶覺
Only private dicks sleep late.
-你正在做一個好夢!  -我正在去曼德勒路上
- Quite a dream you were having! - I was on my way to Mandalay.
他媽的!你這兒的天花漏了!
Shit! There's some leak up there!
這兒!這是你的名字嗎?
Here! ls this your name?
你住的旅館?
That your hotel?
-就是現在這  不是嗎?  -你的筆跡?
- You're standing in it, ain't you? - Your handwriting?
我想是的
I think so.
那也許你能告訴我們...
Then perhaps you can tell us why we found it in the hand
為什麼我們在一個死的吉他手的手媯o現這些
of a dead guitar player.
土斯·史威特死了?
Toots Sweet is dead?
這家夥花了很長時間才死的
This one wasn't so quick, this one took time.
他怎麼死的?
How did he die?
技術上說?他被自己的生殖器給憋死了
Technically? Asphyxiation by his own genitalia.
實際上呢?
And not so technically?
有人切掉了他的生殖器並塞進了他的嘴
They cut his dick off and choked him with it.
然後用他的血把他家重裝飾了一遍
Then redecorated his apartment with his blood.
你何時見過他?
When did you see him?
-1:00左右  -談了些什麼?
- I interviewed him around 1 :00. - About what?
一個失蹤的人
A missing person.
誰?
Who?
一個12年前離家出走的人
A guy who took a walk 1 2 years ago.
有他和土斯的一張相片
There was a photo of him and Toots.
你正在找的人是誰?
Who is the party you're looking for?
我不能說  我正在為一位紐約的律師工作
I can't say. I'm working for a New York lawyer.
-名字?  -好了  哥們兒!
- Name? - Come on, man!
瓦恩薩普!你想要他的電話  地址嗎?
Winesap! You want his number, his address?
去問泰絲·特魯哈特  在他看的那個本子
Ask Tess Truehart over there, it's in the book.
在"W"下面  天才!
Under "W," genius!
你認識泰德.威廉斯  那個棒球運動員?
Do you know Ted Williams, the baseball player?
好吧  就這樣行了吧?
Alright, is that it, guys?
好了
That's it.
你可以去吃午餐  但不要走得太遠
You can go eat lunch, but don't stroll too far.
等我們和這個律師談完再說
Not until we talk to this lawyer.
看過那部"米老鼠俱樂部"嗎?
Ever watch the "Mickey Mouse Club?"
你知道今天是星期幾嗎?
Do you know what today is?
今天是星期三
Today is Wednesday.
是"任何事都可能發生"的日子
It's "anything can happen" day.
嗨  你想要聽歌嗎?
Hey man, do you want a tune?
好吧  我來點首歌
Yeah, I got a tune for you.
你好  小夥子們!
Hiya, boys!
我肚子有點餓
Same to you. I'm getting kinda hungry.
可以賣給我一些嗎?
Do you want to sell some of those?
-10仙一袋  -好的  給我一袋
- 10 cents a sack. - Sure, give me a sack.
聽好了!瑪格麗特·克洛斯馬克的老爸
Listen good! Margaret Krusemark's old man...
希望你坐第一班火車回家
wants you on the first train home.
把那個狗東西拿開!
Take that fucking thing away from me!
如果你不走  這只狗會把你的臉吃掉
Don't, or the dog will bite your fucking face clean off.
你發生了什麼事?
What happened to you?
一只狗咬了我
A dog bit me.
那  你想要什麼?
So, what do you want?
現在  我想把衣服洗一下
Right now, I need a laundry.
-聽我說  艾普芙尼...  -艾普芙尼
- Listen, Epiphiny...- Epiphany.
有件事我想問你
There's something I want to ask you.
有一天晚上我看見你和土斯拿著公雞在跳舞
The other night I saw you and Toots boogying with the cock-a-doodle.
看上去好像在進行一個舞會
Looked like you were having some party.
你看不慣嗎?這是一個自由的國家
What's your problem? It's a free country.
-只要不是雞就行  -哦是的  你對雞過敏
- Not for chickens. - Oh yeah, your thing about chickens.
聽我說  土斯是...
Listen, Toots is...
-土斯死了  -我知道  我聽說了
- Toots is dead. - I know, I heard.
-是你害了他  -不  我沒有
- You set him up. - No, I didn't.
只有你知道我見過土斯.
You were the only one that knew I was seeing Toots.
是你送的那個雞腳  是不是?
You sent the gift-wrapped chicken foot, didn't you?
土斯的嘴太快了
Toots had a big mouth.
我想是的  猜猜警察在他嘴媯o現了什麼
I guess he did, judging by what the cops found in it.
真是個可愛的宗教!
Quite a cute religion!
用釘子把人釘在十字架上也不是很可愛嗎!
Nailing a man to a cross ain't so cute either!
你一定要殺雞去做湯  嗯?
You've got to kill the chicken to make the soup, eh?
我們並不會整天去謀害別人
We don't go around murdering people.
你那個強尼·菲佛瑞又怎麼樣呢?
What about your Johnny Favorite?
-現在你記起他來了  -是的  他是我的父親
- Now you remember him after all. - Yes, he was my father.
我等會兒來接他  好嗎?
I'll pick the baby up later, okay?
放心吧  他沒事的
He'll be all right.
以前你隱瞞的事  現在正是講出來的好機會
Anything you're holding out, now is a good time to tell.
我沒什麼好說的
Nothing to tell.
強尼沒有從戰場上回來
Johnny never came back from the war.
媽媽滿懷憂愁  孤單的一直等到死
Mama waited and Mama died. Sad and simple.
這埵漯漱H太多了...
There's too many dead bodies floating around, even for Louisiana.
我會告訴你丈夫好好照顧你
I'd tell your old man to look out for you.
-你有丈夫吧?  -沒有
- You do have a husband? - No.
沒有?
No?
天哪  你的眼睛真漂亮!
Jesus, you've got beautiful eyes!
真的  不騙你
Really.
這種眼睛會把心媟Q的都說出來
The kind of eyes that tell what's going on inside.
-現在  你被嚇壞了  -我能應付
- Right now, you're scared. - I'll manage.
-聽著...  -知道了  我有消息會打電話給你的
- Listen...- Yes, I'll call you if I hear anything.
有沒有都要打給我
Call me if you don't.
好嗎?
Alright?
這有你一個短信
I have a message for you.
-謝謝你  -不客氣
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
-我很高興你能來  -我不知道你也在這
- I'm so glad you could come. - I didn't know you were in town.
我正在賽佛魯治(位於洛杉磯)演講
I'm speaking in Baton Rouge...
突然想了解你進展得怎麼樣?
and thought I'd catch up on your progress.
我會告訴你的
I'll tell you,
進展不太好
the progress ain't too good.
到目前為止  我發現了很多東西
I've found out a lot of stuff,
但就是沒有強尼·菲佛瑞
but so far...no Johnny Favorite.
真不好運!
How unfortunate!
現在所掌握的全是一些零碎沒用的和...
All I've got is a belly full of hocus-pocus and...
三具僵硬的...
3 stiffs.
屍體  賽佛先生
Dead bodies, Mr. Cyphre.
謀殺
Murders.
福勒  強尼的醫生  自殺了
I got Fowler, Johnny's doctor, bumped himself off.
老伏都教徒土斯·史威特
This old voodoo guy Toots Sweet.
被自己身上用來小便的東西給憋死了...
He got choked to death with a part of the body meant for pissing with...
這是教堂!
This is a church!
這些事都和一個宗教有關  非常怪異
The whole thing has to do with religion. It's very weird.
我不了解它  它很嚇人
I don't understand it. It's ugly.
有人說已經有足夠多的宗教讓人學會仇恨  而不是愛
They say there's enough religion to make men hate each other but not love.
有人這麼說嗎?
Do they say that?
我告訴你  強尼·菲佛瑞的周圍可沒那麼多愛
I'll tell you something. There wasn't much love around for Johnny Favorite.
他運氣不好!
He was bad luck!
我已是惹禍上身了  我現在是兩宗謀殺案的嫌疑人
It's starting to rub off on me. I'm a murder suspect already in two cases.
警察在土斯·史威特的手媯o現了我的名字和地址
The police found my name and my address in Toots Sweets' hand.
我知道  瓦恩薩普告訴我了
I know, Winesap told me.
你一定要小心  安卓先生
You must be careful, Mr. Angel.
第三個謀殺案呢?
And the third murder?
我查了強尼過去的一個女朋友
I checked out Johnny's old society girlfriend,
瑪格麗特·克洛斯馬克
Margaret Krusemark.
-你認識她嗎?  -有點印象
- Do you know her? - Vaguely.
有點印象?我受夠了這種含糊其辭
Vaguely? I'm a little fed up with fucking vaguely.
這種含糊的用詞快把我逼瘋了  說老實話...
"Vaguely" is putting a noose around my neck and I'm choking, so...
你到底認不認識她?
Did you know her or not?
我聽說過她  但是我沒實際接觸過
I knew about her, but I never actually knew her.
告訴你  她正在給我做圖表
Tell you what, she was doing my chart.
我給了她強尼的生日  2月14日
I gave her Johnny's birthday, February 14th.
然而有人到她那  帶著自己的情人節卡片
Except someone got to her and took out their own Valentine's card.
他們開了她的膛  挖了她的心
They slit her open and cut out her heart.
我想她連自己的未來也無法預測
I guess she couldn't predict the future for herself.
未來並不是想像的那樣
The future isn't what it used to be.
-你的結論呢?  -我沒有任何結論
- And your conclusions? - I haven't any.
我所知道的就是強尼正在給他認識的每一個人惹麻煩
All I know is that Johnny is running around bumping off everyone he knew.
而且越來越多  在中間牽線搭橋的正是我
And more and more, it's me who's on the line for it.
我正在落入其中的圈套
I'm being set up...
而且這些事把我嚇得膽都快破了!
and it's scaring the shit out of me.
所以...請你幹脆實話告訴我
So why don't you just level with me and tell me...
這堥鴝野L媽的是怎麼回事?
what the fuck is going on?
沒別的  我只是想找回強尼·菲佛瑞
Just Johnny Favorite...
和他欠我的債務
and the debt that's owed to me.
我在個人榮譽方面思想很保守
I have old-fashioned ideas, about honour.
以牙還牙  以眼還眼  就這麼簡單
An eye for an eye, things like that.
你他媽到的是幹什麼的?
Who the fuck are you?
注意你的用詞!
Watch your language!
我他媽的才不管這麼多  管他媽的什麼教堂
I don't give a fuck, if this is a church.
-我不喜歡教堂  -你是一個無神論者嗎?
- I don't like churches. - Are you an atheist?
是的  我來自布魯克林
Yes, I'm from Brooklyn.
我會在這塈b一兩天
I'll be in town for a day or two,
找到什麼新線索及時通知我
let me know what else you find,
-如果你缺錢的話...  -不缺!
- and if you need more money...- No!
但是如果我不小心的話  你給我的五千塊錢
But if I'm not careful, that 5,000 bucks you gave me could
將會在電椅上給我買一個位子
buy me a seat on the electric chair.
受驚嚇的眼睛不會說謊
Frightened eyes never lie.
來吧!進來!
Come on! Come inside!
-你的孩子呢?  -他在蜜西那埵o會帶著他
- Where's your child? - He's at Mincie's. She'll bring him.
他自己也有個14歲的孩子  他在那兒沒事的
She's got 14 of her own, so he'll be okay there.
你可以呆在這  或者我再另外開個房間給你
You're welcome to stay here, or I can get you a room.
不用了  這兒挺好
No, it's okay.
我想喝一杯  你要嗎?
I'm going to have a drink. Want one?
好吧  隨便來一杯
Well, have one anyway.
我有想...
I've been thinking...
你媽媽到底看上強尼·菲佛瑞他什麼了?
What the hell did your mother see in a guy like Johnny Favorite?
我不知道  不管他有什麼  她把心全交給他了
I don't know. Whatever he had, it sure stole her heart away.
實話告訴你  這家夥是個卑鄙小人
To tell you the truth, the guy was a creep.
她肯定很想他
She sure missed him.
一位淑女怎麼會喜歡  這樣一個到處搞事的壞家夥?
What does a lady see in a guy who runs around chopping up pigeons?
人們常說  男人不壞  女人不愛
They say it's always the bad-asses who make a girl's heart beat faster.
她以前說過關於他的事嗎?
Did she ever say anything about him?
-只談過兩件事  -什麼?
- Just two things. - What?
那個強尼·菲佛瑞和她想像中的魔鬼一模一樣
That Johnny Favorite was as close to true evil as she ever wanted to come.
另一件呢?
What else?
他是一個令人感到恐怖的情人
That he was a terrific lover.
你多大了?
How old are you?
十七
17.
這麼小就有孩子  太年輕了吧?
Kind of young to have a kid, isn't it?
足夠大了
Old enough.
-孩子他爸去哪堣F?  -我從沒見過他
- Where did the father go? - I never knew him.
對不起
I'm sorry.
我不知道為什麼選了這個房間
I don't know why I took this room.
難以想像!
I can't believe this!
在這個地方當精靈擁有過你
It was a Bambouche. When spirits possess you,
大家都把這叫做"chevalier(神交)"
it's called "chevalier."
我知道:Chevrolet(雪佛來)
I know that: Chevrolet.
"chevalier(神交)"
Chevalier.
我就是這麼說的:Chevrolet(雪佛來)
That's what I said: Chevrolet.
被神觸摸過
Mounted by the gods.
原來是神讓你懷孕的?我現在知道了對不起
So the gods got you pregnant? I understand now. I'm sorry.
實際上我不是的  那次是我做愛最舒服的一次
I'm not. It was the best fuck I ever had.
想跳舞嗎?
Want to dance?
在這兒?
Here?
是的  就在這兒
Yes, here.
我今天早上被狗咬了一口  行動有些困難
I got bit by a dog this morning, I can't move around.
你會感覺不到在動
You won't feel a thing.
好的  我可以和你跳舞
Alright, I'll dance with you.
但是你必須答應我
But you've got to promise.
-什麼?  -不要再拿雞來嚇唬我!
- What's that? - No chickens!
好啦  我來了!
Alright, I'm coming!
我應聽得出是誰這樣敲門
I should've recognised the knock.
這次睡懶覺倒有個好理由
At least you got a reason for sleeping late.
在這兒我們從不和黑人亂搞  這樣就不會出現混血兒
Down here we don't mess with jigaboos. The colored folks keep to themselves.
-我不是你們這兒的人  -你把自己割傷了?
- I'm not from down here. - You cut yourself?
狗咬了我一口
Dog bit me.
你查的這件案子
Somebody called Margaret Krusemark figure
有個叫瑪格麗特·克洛斯馬克的人嗎?
in your missing persons case?
沒有  怎麼了?
No, why?
她死了  那個黑人吉他手
She's dead. That nigger guitar player of yours,
他算不了什麼  他是個伏都教徒
he didn't matter a shit. He was into voodoo,
反正每個星期都有人死
they 86 each other every week.
但是這位克洛斯馬克夫人
But this Krusemark dame,
她來自路易斯安那一個有錢人的家庭  白人家庭
she comes from a Louisiana money family.
一星期內死了兩個人  中間有什麼聯系嗎?
Two people bumped off in a week, what's the connection?
死亡現場很相似!
Similar circumstances!
-她的生殖器也被切下來了嗎?  -不是!
- Did she have her dick cut off too? - No!
那個混蛋把她的心挖了出來
Some fucker cut her heart out,
手腳很幹淨  就像個屠夫
neat as a butcher.
我在找的是個失蹤的人  不是個殺人犯
Look, mine's a missing persons, it's not a murder.
-我想知道你找的這些人的名單  -你去對律師說吧
- I want the name of the party you're looking for. - Talk to the lawyer.
我說了那個自負的家夥
I did. A fancy mouthpiece,
像你一樣用大城市的那一套鬼話來敷衍我
gave me the same big city shit as you.
你讓我怎麼說呢?請你和艾菲·克林克滾開
What should I say? Why don't you and Effie Klinker just fuck off
-別管我?  -嘴巴幹淨點兒!
- and leave me alone? - You ass-wipe!
你在拿路易斯安那州的法律開玩笑
You play jump rope with Louisiana law and I'm going to stick
我會死盯著你這個從紐約來的蠢驢的
your big city smarts right up your New York ass.
克洛斯馬克會一些妖術  亂七八糟的東西
This Krusemark was into black magic and all that shit.
警察碰到的最糟的事:就是有人為了
Nothing is worse for a cop than people
無稽  瘋狂的理由殺人
who get killed for nutso reasons.
抱歉搞得一團糟
Sorry about the mess.
也許你可以讓你的的黑人將它整理幹淨
Maybe your nigger can clean it up.
你正在唱什麼?
What are you singing?
強尼·菲佛瑞的歌  我母親過去總愛唱這首歌
It's by Johnny Favorite. My mother used to sing it all the time.
你沒事吧?
You okay?
他媽的!
Shit!
你想要什麼  安卓先生?
What do you want, Mr. Angel?
-我想你應該知道  -為什麼?
- I thought you knew. - Why should l?
你的兩個蠢貨帶著一只狗跟了我幾天了
Two of your morons with a matching poodle have been chasing me for days.
我正在找強尼·菲佛瑞
I'm looking for Johnny Favorite.
據我所知  那個混蛋已經死了
As far as I know, that dance band scumbag is dead.
那個混蛋或許殺了你的女兒
That dance band scumbag probably killed your daughter.
-是誰在雇用你?  -我不能說
- Who is employing you? - I can't say.
-我會付錢的  -他們也會
- I'll pay. - So do they.
12年前  你和你的女兒從醫院堸蔑蔣a走了菲佛瑞
1 2 years ago, you and your daughter snatched Favorite from the nut hatch.
你給了一個癮君子醫生25000塊
You gave a junkie doctor 25 grand
讓他偽造強尼還在那堛漕さ
to pretend Johnny was still there.
直到一個星期前  你的圈套還沒被識破
You did a good job until a week ago.
你用的是愛德華·開利這個名字
You used the name Edward Kelley.
我們到那邊去吧那堣騆安靜  你還可以嘗我們做的湯
Let's go over here. It's a little private and you can sample our Gumbo.
我的胃有毛病  受不了這兒的夥食
I've got an acid stomach. Cajun cooking kills me.
真可惜!我們這兒的湯做得很地道
Pity about your stomach! You'd have enjoyed our Gumbo.
我就是愛德華·開利  是我付給福勒25000塊
I was Edward Kelley. It was me who paid Fowler the 25 grand.
-強尼認識你嗎?  -不認識
- Did Favorite know you? - No.
他像一個夢遊的人  呆呆地看著窗外
He acted like a sleep walker. He looked out of the window at the lights.
-你把他帶到哪堨h了?  -時代廣場1943除夕夜
- Where were you taking him? - Times Square. New Years Eve, '43.
我們在人群中放走了他  而他就永遠地消失了
We dropped him off in the crowd, and he disappeared forever.
就這麼回事
Or so we thought.
你是說你花了25000塊把他弄出來
You're telling me you paid 25 grand for a guy
然後就在人群中把他放了?
and lost him in a crowd?
我這麼做是為了我的女兒
I did it for my daughter.
有些人認為他倆在逢場作戲
Some sort of hocus-pocus she and Johnny
可我知道  她已不能自拔
were fooling with. She was obsessed.
我知道  我在她的房間中發現一只被做成木乃伊的手
I know, I found a mummified hand in her room.
光榮的手  它可以打開任何的鎖
The hand of glory. It's supposed to open any lock.
它是一個殺人犯的右手上絞刑架前  被切了下來
It was the right hand of a murderer, cut off while his neck was in the noose.
瑪格麗特是這麼認為的
That's what Margaret believed.
妖術!
Black magic!
妖術  法術  又有什麼區別呢?
Black, white, what's the difference?
瑪格麗特總是...
Margaret was always...
-邪惡  -邪惡個屁
- Evil. - Evil as a dunghill.
總是有人說三道四  瑪格麗特並不邪惡
Everyone speaks about someone else. Margaret wasn't evil.
她只是個奇怪的孩子!
She was a strange kid!
她會認字前  就會用紙牌算命
She was into Tarot cards before she could read.
-誰教她的?  -一些女傭或女家庭教師  誰知道
- Who got her started? - Some maid, or governess, who knows.
你說的每句話都是在放屁!
Everything you tell me is a crock of shit!
是你教她的!
You got her started!
你是魔鬼崇拜者!
You're a devil worshipper!
黑暗王子保護有力者
The Prince of Darkness protects the powerful.
-狗屁!  -你不信我也沒辦法
- Shit! - I can't help if you don't believe it.
全告訴我  你這個混蛋  否則我現在就幹掉你!
Come straight with me, you slime-bag, or I'll save the state an execution!
是我介紹強尼和我女兒認識的  他很強大
I introduced Johnny Favorite to my daughter.
我親眼見他在我家堨l喚撒旦  他的道行比我深得多
I watched him conjure up Lucifer in my home. He was deeper in it than me.
他和撒旦簽了契約  他出賣了他的靈魂
He made a pact with Satan. He sold his soul.
-你以為我會信這些嗎?  -我不在乎!
- You expect me to swallow that? - I don't give a damn!
全是胡扯  你這個騙人的東西!
That's a crock of shit, you lying toad!
-他為了演戲出賣了他的靈魂  -為了演戲?
- He sold his soul for stardom. - For stardom?
撒旦在暗中幫他
Satan rose from the depths.
但是他想瞞騙黑暗的王子
But he tried to outwit the Prince of Darkness.
當他變得強大的時候  他想偷偷躲開
When he made it big, he tried to duck out of it.
狗屁!
That's a crock of shit!
強尼從古代的手稿媯o現了一種黑暗儀式
Johnny found an obscure rite in an ancient manuscript.
他需要一個犧牲品
He needed a victim.
要和他同年同月同日出生
Someone his own age.
-為什麼?  -好偷取他的靈魂
- Why? - To steal their soul.
土斯和強尼選中了一個年輕的士兵
Toots and Johnny picked up a young soldier.
-是誰?  -只是一個除夕夜在紐約
- Who? - Just a soldier
慶祝新年的的士兵
celebrating New Year's Eve in New York.
他們把他帶回了強尼住的旅館
They took him back to Johnny's hotel,
在那堨L們舉行了黑暗儀式
where they had the ceremony.
什麼儀式?
What ceremony?
那個男孩被脫光了衣服
The boy was bound naked on a rubber mat,
綁在一個寫滿各種咒語的橡膠墊子上
there were complicated incantations.
他的胸前被打上五星的烙印
A pentacle was branded on his chest.
瑪格麗特給了強尼一把處女匕首
Margaret gave Johnny a virgin dagger.
他把那個男孩整齊的切開  吃了他的心
He sliced the boy clean open and ate his heart.
當他吞下去的時候  那顆心仍在跳動
It was still beating when he wolfed it down.
強尼想要變成那個士兵
Johnny wanted to become that soldier.
但他還沒有轉變完  就被應召入伍了
Before he had worked it out, he was drafted,
後來受傷被遣送回家的時候  已經忘記自己的身份
injured and sent home without even knowing who he was.
那個男孩是誰?
Who was the boy?
只有強尼知道
Only Johnny knew.
他把姓名牌放在一個花瓶堨瘚馱F瑪格麗特
He put the dog tags in a vase and gave it to Margaret.
把他在時代廣場放走也是瑪格麗特的主意
It was Margaret's plan to drop him off in Times Square.
那是他在出事前記得的最後一個地方
The last place he remembered before it happened.
他需要一個犧牲品  要和他同年同月同日出生
He needed a victim. Someone his own age.
偷取他們的靈魂
To steal their soul.
他把那個男孩整齊的切開並吃了他的心
He sliced the boy clean open and he ate his heart.
那個男孩是誰?
Who was the boy?
強尼想變成那個士兵
Johnny wanted to be the soldier.
也許他已得到了那個家夥的靈魂
Maybe he gained the guy's soul,
但在我看來  他仍是強尼
but he still looked like Johnny to me.
我知道我是誰了!
I know who I am!
唉...
Alas...
耍些小聰明而沒給自己帶來任何好處
How terrible is wisdom if it brings
那真是太可悲了  強尼
no profit to the wise, Johnny.
路易士.賽佛...
Louis Cyphre...
"撒旦!"
"Lucifer!"
連你的名字也是個該死的笑話
Even your name is a dime store joke.
"梅菲斯特(惡魔)"這個名字
"Mephistopheles" is such a mouthful
在曼哈頓是廣為人知的  強尼
in Manhattan, Johnny.
你以為嚇住了一個迷信的老吉他手
Do you think posing as the devil,
一個女巫和剛才那個老家夥
just because it scared a superstitious old guitar player,
就可以以魔鬼的身份出現
and that witch, and that nutty old man,
來嚇唬我嗎?沒必要  我知道我是誰
do you think it's going to scare me? It ain't, because I know who I am.
你殺了他們  還想陷害到我身上
You killed them, and you're trying to pin it on me.
我知道我是誰
I know who I am.
如果我有分開的蹄子和尾巴的話
If I had cloven hooves and a tail,
你會不會覺得更有說服性
would you be more convinced?
你是神經病
You're crazy.
我知道我是誰  你想陷害我
I know who I am. You're trying to frame me.
你想陷害我
You're trying to frame me.
我知道我是誰是你殺了他們  我沒殺過任何人!
I know who I am. You murdered them people! I never killed nobody!
我沒有殺福勒
I didn't kill Fowler,
我沒有殺土斯
I didn't kill Toots,
我也沒有殺瑪格麗特或克洛斯馬克
and I didn't kill Margaret or Krusemark.
我一個人也沒殺
I killed no one.
-恐怕是你做的  強尼  -我的名字不是強尼!
- I'm afraid you did, Johnny. - My name's not Johnny!
所有人都是你殺的  很自然  是在我的引導下
All killed by your own hand. Guided by me, naturally.
從你把那個男孩切開那一刻開始就注定會這樣
You were doomed from the moment you slit that young boy in half.
這12年來  你都是活在別人的記憶和生活中
You've been living on borrowed time and another man's memories for 1 2 years.
-我想告訴瓦恩薩普  他知道的!  -他死了
- I want to tell Winesap, he knows! - He's dead.
可怕的意外!
Nasty accident!
別擔心  不會有人因少了個律師而傷心
Don't worry, no one will mourn one less lawyer.
反正每天都會有人死
Death's everywhere these days.
是什麼讓人生活的有價值呢?
But what gives human life its worth, anyway?
是因為有愛和恨
Because someone loves it, hates it.
血肉身軀是短暫的  只有靈魂是永遠的
The flesh is weak. Only the soul is immortal.
而你的靈魂是屬於我的!
And yours belongs to me!
我知道我是誰
I know who I am.
好了  強尼  仔細看一下吧!
That's it Johnny, take a good look!
不管你多麼聰明地掩飾你的所作所為
However cleverly you sneak up on the mirror, your reflection
但從你的眼神中  事實總是會反映出來
always looks you straight in the eye.
我知道我是誰
I know who I am.
我知道我是誰!
I know who I am!
你回來幹什麼?
Why did you come back?
我住在這兒
I live here.
她是誰?
Who is she?
她肯定不是:安卓  哈勒德
She ain't: Angel, Harold.
她是我的女兒
She's my daughter.
胡說!她是誰?
Bullshit! Who is she?
艾普芙尼·普勞德富特
Epiphany Proudfoot.
她只在這兒呆了一會兒
She stayed here for a little while.
但你有足夠的時間殺了她?
Long enough for you to kill her?
難道不是你的家夥把她搞死的嗎?
Or ain't that your gun up her snatch?
你會為此受到懲罰的
You're going to burn for this.
我知道
I know.
在地獄!
In hell!